<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<quiz>
<question type="multichoice">
    <name>
        <text>Q1 NAR Transcription Rate</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
        <text>In a negative auto-regulation circuit, what happens when you increase the maximum transcription rate while keeping other parameters constant?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
        <text>The maximum transcription rate affects both the response time and steady state level in negative auto-regulation. A higher transcription rate leads to faster accumulation of the protein, which then more quickly reaches the threshold needed for auto-repression. The steady state also increases because the stronger production can maintain a higher concentration even with negative feedback.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>true</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>abc</answernumbering>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Response time increases but steady state remains the same</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. A higher transcription rate actually decreases response time due to faster protein accumulation. The steady state also changes due to the shifted balance between production and repression.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Response time and steady state both decrease</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. While response time does decrease, the steady state actually increases with higher transcription rate as the system can maintain a higher concentration despite negative feedback.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100">
        <text>Response time decreases and steady state increases</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Correct! Higher transcription rate leads to faster protein accumulation (decreased response time) and can maintain a higher steady state level despite negative feedback.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Only steady state increases, response time unchanged</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Both response time and steady state are affected. The faster production rate leads to quicker approach to steady state.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Neither response time nor steady state changes</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Both response time and steady state are affected by changes in transcription rate in a negative auto-regulation circuit.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
</question>

<question type="multichoice">
    <name>
        <text>Q2 NAR vs Simple Regulation Response Time</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
        <text>When comparing the response times of simple regulation and negative auto-regulation:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
        <text>Negative auto-regulation is a speed-up mechanism in gene circuits. The key to this behavior is that when the maximum transcription rate is high, the initial production is very fast, and then the negative feedback kicks in to prevent overshooting. This makes it faster than simple regulation which approaches steady state more gradually.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Simple regulation is always faster</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Negative auto-regulation is actually designed to speed up response times compared to simple regulation.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Both systems have identical response times</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. The systems have fundamentally different dynamics due to the presence of feedback in the auto-regulated system.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100">
        <text>Negative auto-regulation reaches steady state faster with higher maximum transcription rate</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Correct! The high initial production rate combined with negative feedback creates a faster approach to steady state compared to simple regulation.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Response time is independent of regulation type</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. The type of regulation significantly affects response time dynamics.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Simple regulation has more predictable response times</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Both systems have predictable response times, but negative auto-regulation is consistently faster.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
</question>

