<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<quiz>
<question type="multichoice">
    <name>
        <text>Q29 NAR Similarity to Simple Regulation</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
        <text>In negative auto-regulation, the system becomes more like simple regulation when:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
        <text>The distinctive features of negative auto-regulation (faster response time, reduced noise) depend on having a higher maximum transcription rate than simple regulation. When these rates become similar, the advantages of negative auto-regulation disappear, making it behave more like simple regulation.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>The cooperativity increases</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Higher cooperativity actually makes the system less like simple regulation by enhancing the feedback response.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Activation threshold decreases</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Lower thresholds don't make the system behave more like simple regulation.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100">
        <text>Maximum transcription rate approaches that of simple regulation</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Correct! When the transcription rates are similar, the advantages of negative auto-regulation disappear, making it behave more like simple regulation.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Degradation rate increases</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Changes in degradation rate affect both systems similarly and don't make them more alike.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>The initial concentration is high</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Initial conditions don't affect the fundamental differences between the regulatory mechanisms.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
</question>

<question type="multichoice">
    <name>
        <text>Q30 AND FFL Delay Tuning</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
        <text>The most important parameter for tuning the AND feed-forward loop's delay is:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
        <text>The delay in an AND feed-forward loop is primarily determined by how long it takes the intermediate regulator to reach its activation threshold. This time is most directly controlled by the ratio between the threshold and the steady state level, as this determines how much accumulation is needed for activation.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Input signal threshold</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. While important for activation, this isn't the primary determinant of delay time.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100">
        <text>The ratio of intermediate regulator threshold to its steady state</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Correct! This ratio determines how long it takes to accumulate enough intermediate regulator for activation, directly controlling the delay time.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Target gene production rate</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Target gene production doesn't affect the delay timing.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Input signal degradation rate</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Input signal degradation isn't a primary determinant of delay time.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>The initial concentration of target gene</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Initial target gene concentration doesn't affect the system's delay time.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
</question>    
</quiz> 