<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<quiz>
<question type="multichoice">
    <name>
        <text>Q10 NAR vs Simple Regulation Response Time Difference</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
        <text>The response time difference between simple regulation and negative auto-regulation is most pronounced when:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
        <text>The speed advantage of negative auto-regulation comes from its ability to quickly produce protein initially and then self-limit production. This effect is most noticeable when the maximum production rate in the auto-regulated system is much higher than in simple regulation, allowing for faster initial accumulation.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Both systems have low production rates</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Low production rates in both systems would minimize the difference in response times.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Decay rates are very high</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. High decay rates would affect both systems similarly.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100">
        <text>Maximum transcription rate in auto-regulation is much higher than in simple regulation</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Correct! This allows for faster initial accumulation in the auto-regulated system while maintaining the same steady state.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Hill coefficients are very low</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Low cooperativity would actually reduce the speed advantage of negative auto-regulation.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Activation thresholds are very high</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Very high thresholds would delay the onset of feedback, reducing the speed advantage.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
</question>
<question type="multichoice">
    <name>
        <text>Q11 AND FFL Threshold Effect</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
        <text>In an AND feed-forward loop, increasing the activation threshold of the intermediate regulator will:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
        <text>The delay in an AND feed-forward loop depends on how long it takes the intermediate regulator to reach its activation threshold. A higher threshold means the intermediate regulator must accumulate to a higher level before it can activate the target gene, thus increasing the delay time.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100">
        <text>Increase the delay time</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Correct! A higher threshold means the intermediate regulator needs more time to reach the level required for target gene activation.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Decrease the delay time</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Higher thresholds require more time to reach, not less.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Have no effect on delay time</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. The activation threshold directly affects how long it takes to achieve target gene expression.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Eliminate the delay entirely</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Increasing the threshold cannot eliminate the delay; it actually makes it longer.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Make the delay time unpredictable</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. The delay remains predictable, just longer.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
</question>

<question type="multichoice">
    <name>
        <text>Q12 OR FFL Persistence</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
        <text>The persistence of target gene expression in an OR feed-forward loop is shortest when:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
        <text>Persistence in an OR feed-forward loop depends on how long the intermediate regulator can maintain target gene expression after the input signal is gone. This is primarily determined by how quickly the intermediate regulator degrades below its activation threshold.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Input signal degradation is very low</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Once the input signal is removed, its degradation rate doesn't affect persistence.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100">
        <text>Intermediate regulator degradation is very high</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Correct! High degradation of the intermediate regulator means it quickly falls below the threshold needed to maintain target gene expression.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Target gene production is very high</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Production rate doesn't affect how long the activation signal persists.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Intermediate regulator threshold is very low</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Lower thresholds would actually increase persistence.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Intermediate regulator production is very high</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Higher production would lead to longer persistence.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
</question>

<question type="multichoice">
    <name>
        <text>Q13 I1-FFL Pulse Characteristics</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
        <text>What distinguishes a strong pulse from a weak pulse in the incoherent type-1 feed-forward loop?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
        <text>The strength of a pulse in an I1-FFL is characterized by both how quickly it rises and falls (steepness) and how high it reaches relative to the steady state (amplitude). These characteristics depend on the balance between activation and repression dynamics.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Only the pulse duration</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Pulse strength involves more than just duration.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Only the maximum height</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. The shape of the pulse is also important, not just its height.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100">
        <text>Both the steepness of rise/fall and relative amplitude</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Correct! A strong pulse has both sharp transitions and significant amplitude relative to steady state.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>The initial lag time</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Lag time doesn't determine pulse strength.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>The final steady state level</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Steady state level alone doesn't characterize pulse strength.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
</question>

<question type="multichoice">
    <name>
        <text>Q14 NAR Steady State Sensitivity</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
        <text>The steady state level in negative auto-regulation is most sensitive to:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
        <text>The steady state in negative auto-regulation represents a balance between production and degradation, modified by the feedback strength. This balance is primarily determined by the ratio of maximum production to degradation rates, and where this balance occurs relative to the activation threshold.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>The initial concentration</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Initial conditions don't affect the final steady state in a stable system.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>The cooperativity alone</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. While cooperativity affects the response curve shape, it's not the main determinant of steady state level.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100">
        <text>The ratio of maximum transcription rate to degradation rate and activation threshold</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Correct! These parameters together determine the balance point where production and regulated degradation stabilize.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>The time constant only</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Time constants affect how quickly steady state is reached, not its level.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>The degradation rate alone</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Degradation rate must be considered relative to production rate and threshold.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
</question>

<question type="multichoice">
    <name>
        <text>Q15 AND FFL Input Threshold Role</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
        <text>In an AND feed-forward loop, the role of the input signal's activation threshold is to:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
        <text>The input signal's activation threshold in an AND feed-forward loop determines when both the intermediate regulator and target gene pathways become active. This dual control is essential for the AND logic of the circuit.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100">
        <text>Set the threshold for activation of both intermediate regulator and target gene</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Correct! The input threshold affects both pathways, which is crucial for AND logic operation.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Only affect the production of target gene</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. The threshold affects both the intermediate regulator and target gene pathways.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Control the degradation rate of intermediate regulator</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. The threshold determines activation, not degradation rates.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Determine the final steady state of target gene</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Steady state levels depend on multiple parameters, not just the input threshold.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Regulate the system's noise level</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. While thresholds can affect noise handling, this isn't their primary role in AND FFLs.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
</question>

<question type="multichoice">
    <name>
        <text>Q16 OR FFL Memory Strength</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
        <text>The memory effect in OR feed-forward loop is strongest when:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
        <text>Memory strength in an OR feed-forward loop depends on how long the intermediate regulator can maintain target gene activation after input signal removal. This is maximized when the intermediate regulator degrades slowly and maintains a concentration well above its activation threshold.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100">
        <text>Intermediate regulator degradation is low and its steady state is well above its activation threshold</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Correct! This combination ensures the intermediate regulator maintains activation for the longest time.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Intermediate regulator degradation is high and its steady state is low</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. This would lead to rapid loss of memory.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Target gene degradation is high and its steady state is low</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Target gene parameters don't primarily determine memory duration.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Intermediate regulator production is low and input signal steady state is high</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Low production would reduce memory capability.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>All degradation rates are equal</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Relative degradation rates matter more than equality.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
</question>

<question type="multichoice">
    <name>
        <text>Q17 I1-FFL Production Rate Effect</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
        <text>In the incoherent type-1 feed-forward loop, increasing intermediate regulator production while keeping other parameters constant will:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
        <text>The intermediate regulator in an I1-FFL serves as a repressor. Increasing its production leads to faster accumulation and stronger repression, resulting in a higher but narrower pulse as the target gene is more quickly repressed.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Only increase pulse height</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. The change affects both height and width of the pulse.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Only decrease pulse width</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. The change affects both dimensions of the pulse.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100">
        <text>Increase pulse height and decrease pulse width</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Correct! Faster repressor accumulation leads to a higher but more transient pulse.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Have no effect on the pulse</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Repressor production rate significantly affects pulse characteristics.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Eliminate the pulse entirely</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Higher production modifies but doesn't eliminate the pulse.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
</question>

<question type="multichoice">
    <name>
        <text>Q18 NAR Speed Advantage Loss</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
        <text>The speed advantage of negative auto-regulation is lost when:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
        <text>The speed advantage of negative auto-regulation comes from its ability to initially produce protein at a much higher rate than simple regulation. When the maximum production rates are similar, this advantage disappears as both systems approach steady state similarly.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>The cooperativity is too high</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Higher cooperativity typically enhances the speed advantage.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>The degradation rate is too low</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Degradation rate affects both systems similarly.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100">
        <text>The maximum transcription rate approaches that of simple regulation</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Correct! Without a higher initial production rate, negative auto-regulation loses its speed advantage.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Activation threshold is too high</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. While this affects the response, it's not the primary factor in speed advantage.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Initial concentration is too high</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Initial conditions don't determine the systemic speed advantage.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
</question>

<question type="multichoice">
    <name>
        <text>Q19 AND FFL Signal Filtering</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
        <text>The filtering property of AND feed-forward loop is most effective when:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
        <text>The AND feed-forward loop acts as a signal filter by requiring sustained input long enough for the intermediate regulator to accumulate. Effective filtering occurs when the system's natural delay is longer than typical noise duration but shorter than genuine signals.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Intermediate regulator threshold is very low</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. Low thresholds would reduce filtering effectiveness.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0">
        <text>Intermediate regulator degradation is very high</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Incorrect. High degradation would impair the filtering function.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100">
        <text>The calculated delay is longer than typical noise duration</text>
        <feedback>
            <text>Correct! This ensures noise is filtered out while allowing genuine signals through.</text>
        </feedback>
    </answer>
</question>   
</quiz> 